<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>glusterfs on lwolfs blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.lwolf.org/categories/glusterfs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in glusterfs on lwolfs blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://blog.lwolf.org/categories/glusterfs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to recover data from broken GlusterFS cluster</title>
      <link>https://blog.lwolf.org/post/how-to-recover-data-from-broken-glusterfs-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.lwolf.org/post/how-to-recover-data-from-broken-glusterfs-cluster/</guid>
      <description>A few days ago when I tried to install helm chart in my Kubernetes cluster I noticed that all new pods that required storage were in pending state. After a quick check of the logs, I found out that pods were unable to get PVC from GlusterFS. I recently wrote about my experience deploying GlusterFS cluster. This time I will go through recovering data from the broken GlusterFS cluster, and some problems I faced deploying new cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two days of pain or how I deployed GlusterFS cluster to Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://blog.lwolf.org/post/how-i-deployed-glusterfs-cluster-to-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://blog.lwolf.org/post/how-i-deployed-glusterfs-cluster-to-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>I spent last two days installing GlusterFS storage on top of my Kubernetes. It took much more time and effort than it should. I faced all kinds of problems, some if which were not obvious and took a lot of googling. So I decided to write this post. Hopefully it will save some time for somebody.
I was playing with helm. Trying to assemble a complex application with several dependencies from official chart repository.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>